爸爸
Daddy?
戈登  你没事吧  你在尖叫呢
Gordon, are you okay? You're screaming.
-什么  -你叫得很大声
- What? - You're screaming at the top of your lungs.
-妈妈  -几点了  你怎么起来了
- Mommy! - What time is it? Why aren't you in bed?
要写分析报告
This analysis report--
我周二要去卢博克市  必须把报告写好
I have to leave for Lubbock Tuesday and it has to be perfect.
我把孩子们吵醒了吗
Did I wake up the kids?
说不定把邻居都吵醒了
You probably woke the neighborhood.
-你真没事吗  -没事
- Are you sure you're okay? - Yeah.
宝贝们没事了  妈妈来了
Monkeys, it's okay. I'm coming.
我走之前要给你弄点晚饭吗
Can I get you some dinner before I take off?
都凌晨2点半了还能叫晚饭吗
Can you still call it dinner at 2:30 in the morning?
不用了  黛比  谢谢
I'm good, Debbie. Thanks.
我走之前要给你弄点晚饭吗
"Can I get you some dinner before I take off?"
-别闹  -她说得对  你得吃东西
- Oh, be nice. - She's right. You gotta eat.
你还说别人
Look who's talking.
只工作不玩耍的乔好无聊哦
All work and no play makes Joe a dull boy.
-肯定还有别的办法  -我们都试过了
- There's got to be another way. - We've tried everything.
-想想别的办法啊  -做不到
- Well, get more creative. - I can't.
再这么拆东墙补西墙
I move more things around,
这种状况就掩饰不住了
it's going to start to look bad.
会造成影响的
It'll be a problem.
个人电脑部的运营已经出现巨额赤字
Personal computer division is already operating at a massive deficit.
到了下周末
By close of business next week,
赤字进一步增长  会把整个公司拖下水
the hole will be so deep, it will take the entire company with it.
这事只有你知我知
You keep this between us.
明白吗
Do you understand?
我们不该在这儿吃东西
We shouldn't be eating in here.
我知道
I know.
我就喜欢看着它
I just like looking at it.
让我很性奋
It kinda turns me on.
是不是很怪
Oh, is that weird?
乔  那个通了电的
Joe, that's a live current.
只有几伏
It's only a few volts.
你干什么呢
What are you doing?
让你性奋
I'm turning you on.
来电话了
No, someone's calling.
现在可是凌晨3点
3:00 in the morning.
不  不  我非常高兴
No, no, I'm thrilled you'll do it,
我只是没想到你会回电话
I'm just surprised you called back.
我是给你留了言  但那是几周前的事了
I left you a few messages, but that was several weeks ago.
下周吗
Oh, next week?
我完全不知道他要在这儿开影展
I had no idea he was showing his photos here.
我很想去看
I'd love to see that.
我很想见你  跟你共事
I would love to see you, work with you on this.
6号吗  我很期待
Oh, the sixth. I'll look forward to that.
你最近怎么样
How have you been?
额外的内存空间和卡梅伦的扩展操作系统
Can't say I'm exactly happy about the extra memory
-我并不喜欢  -烤宽面条放在冰箱里了
- or Cameron's expanded O/S... - The lasagna is in the freezer.
放进烤箱加热之前
Don't forget to take it out
-别忘了拿出来解冻  -不过...
- and let it thaw before you reheat it in the oven. - You know,
这都过去了
that's the past.
-我们要向前看  -你要是需要
- We have to move on. - in case you need it
酒店的号码  就在冰箱上
the number for the hotel is on the fridge.
-戈登  听到了吗  -我知道大家怎么说
- Gordon, did you hear me? - I know what people are saying.
他们说我为软件妥协了
They're saying that I roll over for software.
-但事实是...  -戈登  看着我
- But the truth is-- - Gordon, look at me.
宽面条  冰箱  解冻  烤箱
Lasagna, freezer, thaw, oven,
电话在冰箱上  我知道了
number on the fridge. Got it.
质量检测会顺利的
Look, the QA tests, they're gonna go fine.
肯定有不如意之处
There's gonna be disappointment,
但我们要关注净收益
but we need to focus on the net gain here.
-他们得明白  -好吧
- They need to realize that... - Okay,
你送孩子上学
so you're taking the kids to school,
你回来时萝丝就该到了
Rose will be here by the time you get back,
我明天中午回来
and I'll be home by noon tomorrow.
他们要明白  我每天都在那儿
What they need to realize is that I'm in there every day.
敦促乔  以搞到我们需要的东西
I'm pushing Joe to get what we need.
我也会想你的
I'll miss you, too.
有时候我们的思维会...
Sometimes our thoughts are often...
开机时间48.24秒
Boot time's 48.24 seconds.
48  上个月还是39秒呢
48? We were at 39 last month.
操作系统内存导致的  每次开机
OS memory requirements. I mean, the thing's basically
简直就是要600磅的人做蹲起
doing a 600-pound standing squat every time it turns on.
-系统反应时间呢  -403毫秒
- System response time? - 403 milliseconds.
这下多赫蒂阈值没了
There goes the Doherty Threshold.
-重量呢  -只重了几盎司
- Weight? - Only added a few ounces,
但还是超过15磅了
but it puts us over 15 pounds.
是因为多加的内存芯片和子板
It's the extra RAM chips and the daughter board.
我知道原因  有兼容损失吗
I know what it is. Loss in compatibility?
今天早上加载Lotus时没有反应
Tried to load Lotus this morning and it tanked.
那就是有了
I'd call that a big yes.
谈谈名字吧
All right, let's talk names.
软件部不负责命名吗
Oh, you mean software's not naming it?
我会把建议列成单子交给产品经理
I'm gonna take a list of suggestions to the product manager
到时讨论决定
and there's gonna be a discussion.
所以我们还是没机会嘛
So you mean we don't have a chance in hell.
对名字你们到底有没有想法
Do you guys have name suggestions or not?
好吧
Okay.
谢谢
Thank you.
你知道他要来都一周了
Well, if you knew this guy was locked for a week,
为什么今天才让我取消和肯尼的见面
why am I just cancelling Kenny today?
这太突然了  他不会高兴的
It's awful abrupt and he's not gonna be thrilled.
我的人喜怒无常  他是位艺术家
My guy's temperamental. He's an artist.
我们虽然通了几次电话
Despite our back and forth over the phone,
但我并不确定他会不会来
I wasn't even sure he would show up.
但他既然来了  就一定是答应了
But now that he's here, I know he's a yes.
-还有件事  -他说答应了吗
- There's something -- - He say that?
几个小孩入侵了
A bunch of teenagers broke into
洛斯阿拉莫斯国家实验室的电脑
Los Alamos National Lab's computers,
还有一个癌症中心和一家大银行
also into some cancer center and a big bank.
大多是用虚拟机操作系统的数字设备公司
Most were DECs running VMS OS.
都上封面故事了  太帅了
God, cover story and everything. Pretty cool.
你偷了我的车
You stole my car.
我只偷了你的钥匙
I stole your keys.
我把钥匙插进去时  车子自己启动了
The car just turns on when I put them in.
西蒙·丘奇  见到你真高兴
Oh, Simon Church. It's fantastic to see you.
谢谢你不辞辛苦来到这里
Thank you for making the trip all this way.
你对我和这个项目的意义无比重大
I can't tell you how exciting this is for us and the project.
是吗
Right.
我也很高兴
Hello to you, too.
很抱歉我迟到了  害你久等了
I'm sorry I'm late. I know I've kept you waiting.
但我还有点小事需要处理
I just have a few things to get in order.
你能不能在会议室等我们呢
Would you mind waiting for us in the conference room?
我都等不及要看看你的设计了
I can't wait to see what you've put together.
黛比
Debbie?
今天我们能成熟点吗  就几个小时
You think today maybe we could be adults? Just for a few hours?
是  长官  麦克米伦先生  长官
Uh, yes, sir, Mr. MacMillan, sir.
他是世界上最棒的工业设计师之一
He is one of the top industrial designers in the world.
如果他给我们做机箱  我们就能上一个档次
If he makes our case, it puts us on a whole new level.
只是开个玩笑  很抱歉行了吗  真是
It was a joke, okay? I'm sorry. Jesus.
你知道我今天要开会
You knew I had this meeting today.
我先说吧
I'll go first.
这样的轮廓  设计  角度  简直是
The contour, the design, the angles, it--
我只能赞叹  这正是我们想要的
All I can say is wow. It's exactly what we wanted.
很高兴能让你满意
So glad that I could accommodate.
我认为这做的很棒
I think this is something very special.
真漂亮  我能说句话吗
Yeah, it's a pretty girl. C-can I say something?
参数发给你有一周了  你没看吗
What happened to the specs that you've had for a week?
我看了  但是它们局限性太强
I saw them, but they were too limiting.
不局限于参数  我们才有机会创造更好的东西
Moving past the specs gives us an opportunity to make something,
而不仅仅是一个米黄色长方块
something that isn't just a beige rectangle.
那些长方块耗费了数月的...
Okay, those rectangles took months and months of--
你觉得你可以大摇大摆地进来
Do you think you can just waltz in here
要求我们改变一切
and demand that we change everything
就只是因为你不喜欢它的外观吗
'cause you don't like the way that it looks?
-没错  -好吧
- Yes. - Okay.
我们会重新设计来满足你的要求
Okay, well, we'll redesign the whole thing to fit the suit.
我看到你给康塔什和德劳瑞恩做过设计
I saw that you worked on the Countach and the DeLorean.
均为汽车品牌
我告诉你吧
Let me tell you what I know.
这两种车都是修理店的常客
Both are in the shop every hundred miles.
没有人会在意
Nobody gives a damn about
电脑的外观  只要它好用就行
what the computer looks like as long as they work.
我来告诉你吧
Let me tell you what I know.
你的顾客很快就会有十几种可选电脑
Your consumers will soon have more than a dozen choices
看起来都和你造的电脑一样
that look identical to what you'd build,
那么用什么来吸引他们的注意力
so what will capture their attention?
是设计  让他们每次触摸你的机器时
A design that they will be magnetically drawn to
就被深深吸引
every single time they move to touch your machine.
乔  这设计需要我们彻底修改硬件
Joe, this design will require another hardware overhaul.
要花费上百小时
I'm talking hundreds of hours.
我们在散热方面是领先的
The one place that I'm ahead is heat.
如果我为此扔掉散热器...
If I ditch the sink for this, I run--
等我们推出"尾迹"  如果它是这个样子
When we unveil the Contrail and it looks like this,
人们会为它疯狂的
people will be falling over themselves.
等等  你管它叫什么
Wait, the what?
"尾迹"  我们要叫它"尾迹"
The Contrail. We're calling it the Contrail.
我这周会宣布  所以暂时保密
I'm announcing it this week, so don't tell anyone.
"尾迹"  你要用飞机喷出的尾气
The Contrail? You're naming it after the exhaust
来为它命名
that comes out of the back of a plane?
含义在于腾空而起  将竞争对手留在扬尘里
It's about soaring, leaving the competition in the dust,
这设计也正能做到这一点
which is exactly what this design can accomplish.
不  乔  尾迹就是指扬尘
No, Joe, contrail is the dust.
如果我们继续本末倒置
Look, if we continue to put form ahead of function,
被甩在后面遭人嘲笑的就会是我们
we're gonna be the ones left behind with everyone laughing at us.
你怎么不叫它...
I mean, why don't you just call it--
叫它"卡迪夫巨人"
call it the "Cardiff Giant"?
你向我保证过不会有问题
You assured me that everything was in line
不会浪费我的时间
and that my time wouldn't be wasted.
我没时间让你浪费
I don't have time to waste.
这是什么意思  我以为你是答应了
What is this? I thought this was a done deal.
你千里迢迢飞过来  现在却要走了吗
You fly out all this way and now you're leaving?
我为了这次会面解雇了另一个设计师
I let another designer go just to take this meeting.
-那女孩是怎么回事  -就因为这个吗
- What's with the girl? - Is that what this is about?
我根本就不该来
I never should've come.
他走了  你满意了吗
He's gone. Are you happy?
就因为你不喜欢这个名字
All because you didn't like the name?
你想管它叫什么
What did you want to call it?
"巨人"吗  好  那就叫"巨人"
The Giant? Fine. It's the Giant.
我会让市场部扔掉设计从头开始
I'll have marketing toss the art and start from scratch.
除了要调整大小  设计大半用的是金属
Hey, regardless of the resizing, half the design was metal.
你希望每次把电脑放膝盖上
You want your Armani pants to
你阿玛尼的裤子就会着火吗
catch on fire every time you put it in your lap?
我觉得  你不肯接受
I think you act like you can't see it
是因为你其实根本做不到
because the truth is you can't do it.
我看完了整本杂志  谢谢
I read a whole magazine-- thank you.
有人给我做早餐  有人给我女儿做早餐
Someone made me breakfast. Someone made my kids breakfast.
简直是翻天覆地的变化
It's a revolution.
你一定觉得我太嫩了...
You must think I am just the greenest--
不  现在都没人对出差这么兴奋了
No, no, no one I know gets excited about business trips anymore.
尤其是这趟差
Especially this trip.
为什么  我们要给他们呈递99/4A的修改方案
Why? We're bringing them fixes for the 99/4A.
我们算是解决方案啊
We're part of the solution.
不知道公司会不会也这么想
Well, not sure corporate sees it that way.
这些修改的作用微乎其微
These are Band-Aids on a sucking chest wound.
那我们为什么不告诉他们实情呢
Well, then why don't we tell them the truth?
我倒是想  但我不想失去我的工作
I would, but I'd also like to keep my job.
-这个级别的高管  -去四层
- Execs at this level... - Four, please.
他们只想听自己想听的  去八层
...they want to hear what they want to hear. Eight, please.
他们让我们作报告
They asked us to present the report,
我们照做就是了
so that's what we're gonna do.
我们先打扮一下  再玩椰菜娃娃
We can play dress-up and then play Cabbage Patch.
开个舞会
A dance party.
妈妈在冰箱里给我们留了烤宽面条
Mommy left lasagna in the freezer.
我们放进烤箱热上  然后玩椰菜娃娃
We could put it in the oven and then play Cabbage Patch.
或者积木  我们可以玩积木
Or blocks. We could play blocks.
没人能决定我们吃什么
No one's gonna tell us what to eat.
我们要自己做吃的
We are gonna make our own dinner all by ourselves.
-妈妈会生气的  -那我们吃什么啊
- Mommy's gonna be mad. - Daddy, What are we gonna eat?
妈妈现在不在
Mommy's not here.
离婚诉求书
我们得把肯找回来
We need to get Ken back.
你在逗我吗
Are you shitting me?
计算机分销商展览还有6周  我们需要机箱
We have six weeks till COMDEX and we need a case.
你要是不希望我用垃圾袋包着机器亮相
Unless you want me to wrap the machine in a garbage bag,
我们就得找个设计师
we need a designer.
寄存器的内存只有256字节  这是个短板
With only 256 bytes of RAM in the register, we have a bottleneck
每次加载都需要等四个周期  让寄存器清空
that sets off a four-cycle wait to clear every time we load it.
-亨特  -而且功率调节器会过热
- Hunt-- - Plus a power regulator that gets so hot,
-用户都叫它"咖啡暖杯器"  -亨特
- users refer to it as the "coffee cup warmer." - Hunt,
你列出了很多问题
you're listing off a lot of problems,
那么解决这些问题也要花很多钱
and a lot of problems means a lot of money for fixes.
我们需要一劳永逸的办法
We need assurances that correcting these
一次性解决所有瑕疵
will solve the computer's flaws once and for all.
不可能的
Well, they won't.
对不起  但是99没法一劳永逸地修好
I'm sorry, but there are no once-and-for-all fixes for the 99.
如果你真想解决问题
If you want to do the right thing,
就把它从我们的产品名录里去掉
you drop it from our product list for good.
她说得对
She's right.
我们还能做什么  再降价吗
I mean, what are we gonna do, slash prices again?
继续打折吗
Hand out another rebate?
我们几乎都是在白送了
We're practically giving it away already.
要我说
If you ask me,
我们就彻底退出个人电脑市场
we get out of the PC market altogether.
太对不起了  我不是故意插嘴的
I am so sorry. I didn't mean to jump in--
唐娜  他们讨论放弃99好几个月了
Donna, they've been toying with dropping the 99 for months.
只是没人敢真正说出口
People are just too scared to say it out loud.
-除了你  -等下  真的吗
- Except for you. - Wait, really?
如果你没那么说
If you hadn't said that,
他们就不会直面事实
they never would've heard the truth.
-真有勇气  -真有傻劲还差不多
- That took guts. - I thought it took stupidity.
你就承认自己的功劳吧
Will you please just take the credit?
我们去楼下吃晚饭吧
Now, I say we meet downstairs for dinner,
当然是公费吃喝
on the company's credit card, of course,
好好庆祝一下我们的成功
and we celebrate a job well done.
7点见
7 o'clock?
好的
Yeah, okay.
她只能自己生火
She had to build her own fire...
自己拾柴
...and gather her own wood.
你好
Hello?
戈登  乔找你
Hi, Gordon. I've got Joe for ya.
但是1898年  艾瑞斯曾祖母
But in 1898, Great-Grandma Iris
在最后的淘金热时  拿了一些钱
picked up some stakes and ran off to the Klondike
去了克朗代克during the last great gold rush.
加拿大一处黄金产地
那时食物很少  得打猎煮饭
Food was scarce. You had to hunt and cook...
全靠自己  从零做起
...from scratch all on your own.
但是艾瑞斯曾祖母非常坚强
But Grandma Iris, she was tough.
她真的很坚强
She was real tough.
这就是她的祖传食谱
And this was her original recipe.
-你坚强吗  -不
- Are you tough? - No.
让她自己回答
Let her speak for herself.
过来
Come here.
让你姐姐瞧瞧你的志气
Show your big sister what you're made of.
-很好吃  爸爸  -是好吃
- It's good, Daddy. - It is good.
我也要一点  我也很坚强
I want some. I'm tough.
-很好吃  -因为你很坚强
- It's good. - 'Cause you're tough.
你也很坚强
And you're tough.
我们都很坚强
We're all tough.
我们能烤饼干吗  爸爸
Can we make cookies, Daddy?
妈妈有那种切下来直接进烤箱的饼干
Mommy has the cut-and-put-in-the-oven kind.
我们能一起玩游戏吗  爸爸
Can we play with you, Daddy?
我们很想跟你一起玩
We really want to play with you.
烤饼干可以  玩游戏可以
Yes to cookies, yes to games,
爸爸的美味炖汤也可以
yes to Daddy's wonderful stew.
你们去洗手吧
You guys go wash up.
看来你今晚不会去那什么摄影展了
I take it you're not going to the photography thing tonight?
不会了
No, actually.
我来换衣服  因为我要和约翰·博斯沃思
I came to change because instead I'm joining John Bosworth
还有肯·波克一起去"柔情爱抚"
and Ken Burke at "Strokers."
那是个名字惊艳的脱衣舞俱乐部
That's a strip club with an incredible name.
看来要用米黄色的机箱了
Beige box it is.
听着  我也不想如此
Look, it's not what I want, either.
要怪就怪戈登  他把一切都搞砸了
Blame Gordon. He blew it up.
你跟西蒙睡过吗
Did you sleep with Simon?
这种事情会困扰你吗
Is that something that would be a problem for you?
我完全不介意他是个男人
I don't give a shit that he's a man.
真的
Honestly.
十年前  我去欧洲参加一个会议
10 years ago, I was at a conference in Europe.
西蒙做了发言  我是听众之一
Simon spoke, I was in the audience.
他...
He was...
我想成为他那样的人
I wanted to be him.
我们一直待到会议结束
We stayed through the end of the event,
在接下来的一个月里游遍了欧洲大陆
traveled around the continent for the next month
然后
and then...
他离开了
he left.
就这样
That's it.
但他今天来你办公室来了
And yet he was in the office today.
他是个才华横溢的设计师
He's a brilliant designer.
我愿意忍受他
I was willing to put up with him
只要这对我们的工作有好处
if it meant something great for the work we've done.
但看来他不过是在玩我罢了
But I guess he was just stringing me along.
抱歉我今早对你发脾气了
I'm sorry I snapped at you earlier.
那家伙让我心神不宁
That guy just messes me up.
那个  给一美元她就肯跳舞
That one, she'll dance for a dollar,
做任何你要她做的事
do anything you like.
我可不会为一美元跳舞
I don't dance for a dollar.
你的报价很合理
Oh, your quote is perfectly reasonable
我们想继续谈了
and we'd like to move forward.
"报价"  价钱要涨了  要涨很多
My quote? It's gone up. Way up.
别这样  肯尼  我们也不是钱做的
Oh, come on, Kenny, man. We're not made of money here.
我们就想要个基本的注射模具
We're talking about a basic injection mold now.
我们俩在同一个圈子里混了好些年了
You and I have been in the same circles for years.
我一向非常敬重...
I've always had the utmost respect--
我们就走马观花地看  一眼就相中了你
We was window-shopping and decided you were the man to marry.
你们只是退求其次
Yeah, you're settling.
我想先受邀去参加舞会
See, I like to get asked to the prom first.
否则  我的感情就很受伤
If I don't, my feelings get hurt.
说到婚姻  靳妮最近怎么样了
Hey, speaking of marriage, how's Ginnie?
靳妮挺好的
Ginnie's doing just fine.
是吗  你做好后备打算了吗
Yeah? You line anything up on the side yet?
我们不是退求其次  而是重视实用性
We're not settling. We're betting on utility.
你的设计很简洁  很有接纳性
Your design is simple, it's welcoming,
没有大肆张扬  而我们想要的就是
it doesn't intimidate, and we want our machine to be...
亲民
friendly.
我都不用给你一美元
Shit, I don't need to give you a dollar.
你会免费跳舞
You'll dance for free.
-你有邀请函吗  -什么  有
- Do you have an invite? - Huh? Yeah.
这他妈是什么
What the hell is this?
你个贱货
You skank.
你是拿我当司机呢  是吧
You used me for a ride, didn't you?
放松点  这里有免费的香槟酒
Relax, there's free champagne.
给你半小时  然后我就走人
30 minutes and I'm leaving your skinny ass.
真苍凉
Bleak.
摄影师非常清楚
I think the photographer understood very well
这地方有多空旷
how empty this place really is.
可不是嘛  这是我家
Tell me about it. I'm from here.
抱歉了
My apologies, then.
彩虹仙子小姐今晚有何贵干呢
So, what can I do for "Miss Rainbow Brite" This evening?
卡通形象
给我们做机箱
Agree to build our case.
你多大了
How old are you?
我已经能看出价值十万美金
Old enough to see the difference between a $100,000 car
只有少数人能买得起的车
that only a fraction of the population can afford
和五年之内所有人
and a utility that every single human being
都能与之交互的设备之间的区别
will be interfacing with inside of five years.
我明白乔为什么喜欢你了
I can certainly see why Joe likes you.
告诉他  派你作第二轮攻势真是漂亮
Please tell him I said bravo for the very clever second push.
不是乔派我来的
Joe didn't send me.
但我知道这对他很重要
But I know this is important to him.
是吗
Important?
乔怎么跟你说我的
What did Joe tell you about me?
我知道你俩搞遍了全欧洲什么的
Look, I know you guys humped all over Europe or whatever.
-我不在乎  -他这么说的吗
- And I don't care. - Oh, is that how he put it?
我记得可不是这样
Because I seem to remember it fairly differently.
-他说我离开他了吗  -说了
- Did he tell you I left him? - Yeah, he did.
说为什么了吗
Did he tell you why?
我告诉他我爱他
Because I told him I loved him,
一说出口我就知道完了
and the moment I said it, I knew it was over
所以第二天早上我就走了
so I left the next morning.
免得丢人
I tried to spare myself the embarrassment.
我们是有过好时光
We did have quite a bit of fun for a while.
纵情深夜
Late nights.
做了好多傻事
Did a lot of stupid things, but
乔后来大概是腻了
in the end, I believe Joe just got bored.
听我说
Listen...
我知道你觉得他对你不一样
I know that you think what you have with him is different,
但不要误以为
but please don't make the mistake of thinking
他最终不会也这么对你
that he won't do the same thing to you eventually.
走吧
Come on, let's go.
等会儿  我才刚拿到酒  过来
Wait, I just got this one. Come here, come on.
我们喝点香槟吧
Hey, let's have some champagne.
那是谁  前男友吗
Who's that, an old boyfriend?
什么  是啊
Hmm? Yeah.
看着就像个混蛋  他说什么了
He looks like a real asshole. What did he say to you?
没什么
Nothing.
手电筒拿稳点  专心点  姑娘们
All right, hold the light steady. Come on, focus, girls.
能玩点别的吗  玩点我们能赢的
Can we play another game? Something we can win?
跟我玩你赢不了的
If you play me, you won't win.
妈妈就没赢过我
But Mommy never wins.
那是她故意输给你
That's because Mommy loses on purpose,
那会教坏你们
which is not a good life lesson.
其实呢  看几点了
In fact, look. Look what time it is.
睡衣时间到  快去穿睡衣
It's PJ time. You guys go get your PJs on.
你们刷完牙我就去
All right, as soon as you brush your teeth, I'll come in there.
能在你床上讲故事吗
Can we have our story in your bed?
可以可以  走吧
Yeah, fine. Fine, just go.
-喂  -是我
- Hello. - Hey, it's me.
我之前打给你来着
I-- I called.
你还好吗
Uh, is everything okay?
不好
No, everything's not okay.
今天谈了机箱的设计
We went over the case design again today
乔又想让我
and once again Joe wants me
推翻重做  配合设计师
to shift everything around inside to accommodate.
重外表轻内在  我受够了
It's style over substance and I'm tired of it.
有人拿了个金属面板的机箱来
Guy comes in and presents something with metal paneling,
因为尺寸问题  散热器装不进去
and because of the dimensions, the heat sink won't fit.
那样回头得热的能当华夫饼铛了
I mean, the thing's gonna end up being a waffle iron.
尺寸我传真给你
I'll fax you over the dimensions
你看看有多荒唐
so you can see how ridiculous it is.
但这是可行的啊
Wait, but that could work, couldn't it?
用外壳来为主板散热
Let the exterior paneling pull heat off the board?
这主意还挺有意思的
It's actually an interesting idea.
戈登
Gordon?
我得挂了
I have to go.
爸爸  我们把睡衣穿好了
Daddy, we have our PJs on!
来啊
Come on.
说到底
At the end of the day,
我们还是很高兴能跟你们合作
we're happy to be doing business with y'all.
我们会设计好机箱的
We'll get you a case.
多谢了  肯尼
Well, I appreciate that, Kenny.
我们很荣幸
The pleasure's ours.
尽快做个塑料模型出来  好吗
Get that plastic mold fired up ASAP, huh?
你们出了那么多钱
We figure with the amount of money you're spending,
我可以先做你们的
I can bump you to the top of the list.
多谢了
I appreciate that.
你没事吧  伙计
Hey, you all right there, partner?
-这周挺累  -挺难受  是吧
- Long week. - Hurts, don't it?
至少我们玩得挺尽兴
Well, at least we got to have a good time
花的还是卡迪夫的钱
on Cardiff's dime, though, right?
-是啊  -好好玩  肯尼
- Yeah, sure. - Have a good one, Kenny.
话说  我们今天看了至少20对漂亮的奶子了
Hey, you know, we must'a seen 20 pretty titties.
你脸上却一个笑容都没有
Not so much as a smile from you.
你是基佬吗
What, are you queer?
你这是袭人  约翰  我要告你
That is assault, John! I will press charges.
我告死你  约翰
I am gonna sue your ass, John!
听着没
You hear me?
没事  我没事  别碰我
All right. I'm good, I'm good. Get your hands off me.
你还能跟你朋友谈拢吗
Can you still make it work with your guy?
我去试试
I can try.
爸爸
Daddy?
很久以前  早在1800年间
A long time ago, way back in the 1800s,
纽约卡迪夫有个农民
there was a farmer in Cardiff, New York.
卡迪夫  跟你公司一样
Cardiff, like your job.
没错  这个农民
Exactly. And this farmer,
他想觉得自己很特别
he wanted to feel special,
于是他建造了一个10英尺的巨人
so he built a 10-foot-tall giant
并埋在了他的地里
and buried it out in his field.
他等了一年
And he waited, and a year went by.
然后他跟他的一些雇工把巨人挖了出来
And then he and some of his workers dug it up.
那些为他工作的人
And the men who worked for him
真以为那个巨人是真的
were convied that the giant was real.
于是  人们就劝他让世人看到这个巨人
And the people told him to show it to the world,
他就那么做了
and he did.
人们从四面八方赶来
And people came from all around.
他觉得自己好特别
And he felt very, very special.
他是那么特别
He was so special
甚至有人提出跟他搭档
that somebody offered to partner with him.
P.T.巴纳姆P.T. Barnum,
19世纪著名演员  马戏团主
职业推销员
an expert salesman.
他们每天都会争执不休
And they fought and they argued day and night
因为那个推销员
because the salesman
想把巨人占为己有
wanted the giant all to himself.
后来呢
What happened?
P.T.巴纳姆  建造了自己的巨人
P.T. Barnum built his own giant.
把它收入自己的马戏团
And he made it part of his circus
还说它是真的
and he claimed that it was real.
他推销技巧很高超
And he was such an expert salesman
结果大家都把农民忘了
that everyone forgot about the farmer...
他被遗弃了
and he was left in the dust,
淹没在尾迹里
in the contrail.
我以为自己准没命了呢
And I swear I was headed for the firing squad.
真没想到啊
Great surprise, huh?
你心思没在这儿啊
You've been far away.
抱歉
I'm sorry, I'm...
因为戈登的来电吗
Ever since Gordon called?
我丈夫
My husband is--
他很了不起
well, he is an amazing man.
他为卡迪夫建造的电脑  简直是奇迹
What he created for Cardiff, it's a miracle.
不管这一路上  他们给他制造了多少困难
No matter how they derailed him along the way,
他还是一次次解决了问题
he made it work at every step.
主板两边装芯片
Chips on both sides of the board,
为扩展操作系统单独配备整整一兆的内存
an entire megabyte of RAM for an expanded OS...
唐娜  你为什么说这些
Donna, why are you telling me this?
因为我们说好的
Because we made a deal.
我们说好  如果他做这个
We agreed that if he did this
结果不会像上次那样
that it wouldn't turn out like last time,
但我觉得他可能没那么坚强
and I just don't think that he's strong enough and I'm--
我觉得我也没那么坚强
I'm not sure that I'm strong enough.
你吗
You?
你很了不起
You are incredible.
你说这钢琴师会不会别的曲子啊
Gosh, you think this piano player knows any other songs?
他们该雇你去弹
They should hire you to play.
是啊
They should.
-看来他要休息了  -谢天谢地
- Uh-oh, looks like he's taking a break. - Good.
-不行  -去吧
- No. - Go on.
-不行啊  -别磨磨蹭蹭的了
- I can't. - Quit your stalling.
好吧
Fine.
去吧
Go on, get up there.
New Orleans Boogie
比之前那人强多了
That's a lot better than that last guy.
你叫什么
What's your name?
苏珊·费尔柴德
Susan Fairchild.
你把我大老远找来就为了闲扯吗
You call me all the way out here just to shoot the breeze?
个人电脑项目没钱了
The PC program's out of money.
-抱歉说的这么直  -慢着
- I'm sorry to land it on you like that. - Wait,
你怎么才说呢
why am I just hearing about this?
怎么回事
What the hell happened?
创新有风险
Innovation is a risk.
那算什么意思
I don't understand even what that means.
你这口气活像乔啊
You sound like Joe, for Christ's sake.
好消息是  我们很快就能出成果了
The good news is we're weeks away from a payday.
等我们在计算机分销商展览上一亮相  内森
The moment we debut at COMDEX, Nathan--
你今晚给了肯·波克面门一拳吗
Did you strike Ken Burke tonight in the face?
-他侮辱靳妮  -他给我打电话来  要气疯了
- He insulted Ginnie-- - He called me up madder'n hell.
我需要你个人给我们一笔
I need you to personally offer us
过渡性贷款  好让我们去展览会
a bridge loan to get us to COMDEX.
你是疯了吗
Are you out of your mind?
到年底我们就能还钱
We're gonna pay you back by the end of the year.
你不知道他们在创造什么  内森
You have no idea what these kids are making, Nathan.
这能改变一切
This could change the-- this could change everything.
五年内  我们每个人
In five years, every one of us
自己家里都能有台这样的电脑
could have one of these damn things in the house.
这可不是小市场
It's not a small market we're talking about.
我们得马上进入这个市场
We gotta get in the door now.
我要抵押我的房子
I'm thinking about putting up my home.
你也得这么做
I need you to match that.
-什么  -没错
- Match? - Yeah.
你是怎么回事
What the hell is wrong with you?
第一条规矩就是不拿自己的钱冒险
Rule number one, you don't risk your own money.
你是被洗脑了  傻了
You've been brainwashed, gone native.
迷失方向的商人什么都不是
Ain't nothing worse than a businessman who's lost his compass.
内森  你以前也信任过我
Hell, Nathan, you trusted me before, damn it.
是我让我们进入大型机市场的
I was the one that got us to mainframes,
-当时你还没疯呢  -我不是...
- Yeah, that's when you were still levelheaded, - didn't I--
当时你还没有
before you started
把我辛苦拉拢的每一个商业伙伴
burning the bridges of every business relationship
都得罪掉
that I have ever forged
你现在又大半夜把我拉来
and now you're dragging me out here in the middle of the night...
要我拿自家土地冒险
asking me to cash in my family's land?
-老天爷啊  -内森
- Jesus, boy. - Nathan!
如果这个项目没钱了
If that program is out of money,
那就是上帝在告诉你
that is God saying,
"歇菜吧  保佑你"
"Good night and God bless."
等没钱了  你就叫停项目
Once the last dime goes, you shut it down.
振作起来  约翰
Pull yourself together, John.
回家到你妻子身边去吧
Go home to your wife.
你知道我见到你的时候  内心渴望什么吗
The moment I met you, you know what I longed for?
有一日我们能合作
The day when we would get to work together,
我们能有配得上你的产品
when we finally had something that would be worthy of you.
你觉得便携IBM克隆机就是了吗
And that thing is a portable IBM clone?
乔  多谢你这么恭维我
Joe, I appreciate the blanket flattery,
但有点晚了吧
but it's a little too late, isn't it?
我不懂  你为什么打给我
I don't get it. Why call me?
你为什么要重新闯入我生活中
Why come back into my life at all?
我记得杰瑞米说要离开纽约
I remember when Jeremy said he was leaving New York
来这儿待一年的时候
to come spend a year here.
他说是要"游历大平原"
"Tour the Great Plains," He said--
俄克拉荷马  德克萨斯  堪萨斯
Oklahoma, Texas, Kansas.
要"拍摄风景"  什么风景啊
"Photograph the landscape." What landscape?
我们都以为他是疯了
I mean, we all thought he'd gone mad.
但我还是来了  想看看他口中的风景
But here I am trying to see what he was talking about,
他拍摄的照片
looking at his pictures,
并努力搞清楚你为什么要搬到这儿来
and trying to to figure out why you moved here.
我告诉你  平等机会  公平竞争环境
I'll tell you why. Equal opportunity, a level playing field--
乔  得了  你那个神童
Joe, please. I already got the hard sell
已经向我推销过这一套了
from your wunderkind over there.
真是年轻一代啊  乔
Truly the future generation, Joe.
她真像当年的你
She actually reminds me of you at that age.
我当时远远不如她
She's light-years ahead of where I was then.
她是未来  这对我们都有益处
She is tomorrow, and we're all better off because of it.
说到底  我们选择谁的设计并不重要
In the end, it doesn't matter what design we choose
因为机器里面的东西才是天才
because it's what's inside the machine that's brilliant.
那是她做到的  不是你  不是我
She did that. Not you, not me.
你做不做机箱  我不在乎
Do the case, don't do the case. I don't care.
放开我  大神探
Get off me, "Kojak." Ow!
行了  过来  过来
All right. Come here, come on.
-振作点  -抱歉
- Get a hold of yourself. - Sorry.
那家伙让我心神不宁
"That guy just messes me up."
等等  好了
Oh, wait a minute. There we go.
你替那个钢琴师挣的小费
You know, you probably made that piano player
大概比他一年的工资还多
more in tips than he makes in a whole year...
苏珊·费尔柴德
"Susan Fairchild."
等等  我好像见过这名字
Wait a minute, I think I know that name.
那是我妈妈婚前的名字
Oh, that's my mother's maiden name.
你大概听过
You probably heard it around.
不是  好像是在哪份报刊上看到的
No, actually, I think I read it somewhere.
你应该经常做苏珊·费尔柴德
You should be "Susan Fairchild" more often.
她挺有意思的
She's fun.
能跟你说句比较私人的话吗
Can I tell you something personal?
你多做了份报告  才来参加这个会议
Doing that extra report got you here.
你向高管说不
Saying no to those execs
改变了我们的汇报
changed our whole presentation.
让人们看到真实的你
Showing people who you really are,
你应该经常这么做
you should do that more often.
大胆一点
Be bolder.
6点楼下见  我们去赶飞机
I'll see you downstairs at 6:00 for our flight.
我们能找到巨人吗
Will we find the giant?
肯定很接近了
I'm sure we're close.
我们得挖深一点
We have to dig deeper, come on.
已经很深了
We're very deep.
天呐  我好像挖到条虫子
Oh, my gosh. I think I found a worm.
是吗  我们给它起什么名字
You did? What should we name it?
笑笑
Smiley?
姑娘们  你们干什么呢
Girls, what are you doing?
挖巨人
Digging for the giant.
小可爱们  那不是真的
No, honey, it's not a real giant.
对他来说是真的  是你说的
It was real to him. You said so.
亲爱的  你们得进去了  要不你们妈妈...
Sweetheart, you gotta get inside or your mother--
没事  爸爸  我们能找到巨人的
Don't worry, Daddy. We'll find the giant.
亲爱的  那只是个故事
Sweetie, it's just a story.
我给你看
Okay, look, I'll show you.
看  没有巨人
See? No giant.
爸爸  你手怎么了
Daddy, what happened to your hand?
爸爸  你没事吧
Daddy, are you okay?
你们待在这里
You guys stay here.
我就回来
All right? I'll be right back.
我找给你们看
I'm gonna show you.
我必须下来一趟...
I just had to come down. I was--
你这是干什么
Whoa, whoa, what-- what are you doing?
你让我大胆些
You said "Bold."
你说...
You said-- wasn't--
我是来给你传真
I came to bring you a fax.
酒店误把这个拿给我了
Um, the hotel delivered it to my room by mistake.
应该是你丈夫发来的
I think it's from your husband.
天呐
Oh, my God.
真抱歉
I am so sorry.
你一定觉得...
I-- you must think that--
不不  这种事也常有
No, no, no. No, look, these things happen, okay?
一起工作的人
Look, people-- people work together
难免会产生...
and they develop, uh, you know--
只是一般不会采取什么行动
they just-- they don't usually act on them.
晚安
Look-- have a good night.
喂
Hello?
还有哪家租车行开着吗
Um, are there any rental car places still open?
是的  现在  我得回家
Yes, now. I need to go home.
新闻周刊  计算机犯罪
414"黑客"  尼尔·帕特里克
明天一早来我办公室
I need you to swing by my office first thing in the morning.
谢谢
Thank you.
我就来
I'll be a minute.
事情并不如我们所愿
This didn't turn out the way either one of us had hoped.
我只是想再见见你  乔
I just wanted to see you again, Joe.
跟你待在一起  跟你合作
Spend some time with you really working on something.
结果却发现你跟她在一起
Then I come to find you're with her.
是啊  我是跟她在一起
Yes, I'm with her.
我们的事都过去十年了  西蒙
What we had was 10 years ago, Simon.
别再留恋过去了
Stop living in the past.
你现在何必还在意那些
Why bother with any of that now?
我病了
I'm sick.
我是来道别的
I just came to say goodbye.
你不问问吗
Aren't you gonna ask?
问什么
What?
你还会不会做机箱
If I'm still gonna do the case?
我了解你  乔  我知道你还在考虑
I know you, Joe. I know you're thinking it.
我上飞机之前就设计好了
I set it up before I even got on the plane.
我希望你知道
I need you to know that
你对我的感觉
the way you felt about me,
我也想...
I wanted to--
保重
Take care of yourself.
走吧
Go.
你也会对我感到腻吗
Are you gonna get bored of me?
我不知道
I don't know.
天呐  宝贝
Oh, my God. Baby?
出什么事了  爸爸呢
Baby, is everything okay? Where's Daddy?
我们刚刚在院子里挖地
We were in the back yard digging.
好吧  去睡吧
Okay. Okay, go back to sleep.
妈妈  我们刚刚在帮爸爸
Hi, Mommy. We were helping Daddy.
戈登
Gordon?
在这儿  我在这儿
Here! Down here!
戈登  你在干什么啊
Gordon, what are you doing?
找巨人
I'm looking for the giant.
人人影视
倾情奉献
翻译
潇湘月影
木浅薰
翻译
七七
小酸奶!
翻译
如是我闻
somehacker
翻译
草草森森被包子叔感动
时间轴
Kallen 芒果树叶
特效
宝宝
电脑狂人
第一季
第七集
校对&总监
草草
后期
饿得慌